Nishikata! Good morning!
西片，早安
Takagi-san! Good morning.
高木同學，早安
I'm on class duty today so I'll go first, okay?
我今天是值日生，所以要早點到學校
Okay.
嗯
Are you gonna be late again today?
西片今天又要遲到了嗎？
Again? I still have plenty of time.
又要？現在還很早呢
Well, see you at school!
好喔，學校見
See you.
學校見
I'm always getting teased by Takagi-san.
我總是被高木同學捉弄
But today's the day I'm gonna get her back!
但今天是我反擊的日子
This is what I spent everyday thinking.
這就是我每天在想的事
A record of my second year of junior high.
這就是我國二時的紀錄
Or rather, my memories.
或者說，是我的回憶
You'd better watch your back,
你最好給我小心點
Takagi-san!
高木同學
Okay, lesson three.
現在進入第三課
Today, we'll be discussing the future tense.
我們今天要來講解未來式
There are two main types of future tense.
未來式主要有兩種
Expressions using "will" and those using "be going to."
使用“將會”和使用“要去”兩種
We'll go through them one at a time.
接下來會逐一解說
Starting with expressions using "will."
首先是“將會”
Let's start with a review.
我們先複習一下
Hey, Nishikata.
嘿，西片
What is it?
幹嘛？
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
Nothing really, why?
沒什麼，怎麼了？
No reason.
沒事
All right, let's talk about the future tense using "will."
好了，我們來講 使用“將會”的未來式
Whoa!
哇！
Yes! This is perfect!
好耶，太完美了
I'll use this to get back at Takagi-san!
我要用這個反擊高木同學！
Just like in Japanese,
和日語一樣
"Watch", "run", "eat" words that express actions are verbs.
“看”、“跑”、“吃” 這些表達動作的字都是動詞
For example…
例如…
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
It's just my pencil case won't open.
我的鉛筆盒打不開
I wonder if it got bent?
我在想是不是變形了？
Can you open it for me?
可以幫我開嗎？
Yeah, I guess.
是可以啦
Whoa!
哇！
Keep it down, Nishikata!
給我安靜，西片！
Sorry!
對不起！
Nishikata, your reactions are priceless!
西片，你的反應好好玩喔
Damn it, she got me.
可惡，又被她捉弄了
And with the trick I had planned!
本來是我要捉弄她的 居然被反將一軍！
Takagi-san asking for my help in the first place is strange.
高木同學會找我幫忙這件事 本身就很可疑
I should have known better!
我早該發現的！
Hey!
我說啊
What? Are you gonna tease me again?
幹嘛？你又要捉弄我？
No.
不是
Lend me your eraser, I forgot mine.
借我你的橡皮擦，我忘記帶我的了
You're clumsier than I thought, Takagi-san.
你還真健忘啊，高木同學
Maybe I am.
可能吧
I've got another one. You can keep it for today if you want.
我有多帶一個 所以你今天都可以留著用
Really? Thanks!
真的嗎？謝了
By the way, do you remember that thing in elementary school,
對了，你還記得我們小學時相信
where if you write your crush's name on an eraser and you use it all up,
把喜歡的人名字寫在橡皮擦上 然後把橡皮擦用完
that person will like you back?
那個人就也會喜歡你嗎？
Yeah, I remember that.
嗯，記得
Thinking back, that was so childish!
回想起來，那好幼稚喔
Childish?
幼稚？
Yeah. There's no way that could be true.
對啊，怎麼可能有用嘛
Don't you think?
你不覺得嗎？
I don't think that, but…
我是不相信啦，但是…
You never tried it?
你沒試過嗎？
No way, I don't have a crush anyway.
怎麼可能？我又沒有喜歡的人
What about when you're stuck on your homework?
那你功課寫不出來的時候呢？
Didn't you ever just start writing your crush's name?
不會不自覺地 開始寫你喜歡的人的名字嗎？
No way, not me.
我才不會
Huh? Really?
喔？真的嗎？
What? It doesn't say anything!
幹嘛？上面什麼都沒寫！
I see…
這樣啊…
I guess you're right.
你說得沒錯
It's so childish.
真的好幼稚
No way. Is there something written on it?
不可能，上面有寫東西嗎？
Hmm? What's wrong?
嗯？什麼？
Even if there is, someone's just playing a trick!
就算有，一定也是有人惡作劇
Just give it back!
還給我
Didn't you say I could keep it all day?
你不是說我今天都可以留著用？
Here.
還你
Nothing's written on it!
上面什麼都沒寫！
I didn't say there was.
我又沒說有
When using "be going to," we use the verb in its original form…
當使用“要去”時 後面要接原型動詞…
Please remember this.
請大家記得
You had your own the whole time!
你明明就有帶橡皮擦！
I told you to keep it down!
我叫你安靜！
Sorry!
對不起！
You're making me laugh so much. Give me a break!
笑死我了，你不要鬧了
That's my line!
這是我要說的話吧！
And so, the question is…
所以，題目是…
Excuse me, may I go to the restroom?
老師，我可以去廁所嗎？
Go ahead.
去吧
So, to make the sentence,
所以，如果要造句的話
"Are you going to visit your friend tomorrow?"
“你明天要去拜訪朋友嗎？”
Damn it… just you wait.
可惡…給我等著
That's it!
對了
I'll write someone's name on her eraser
我也在她的橡皮擦上寫個名字
and trick her when she gets back from the restroom!
然後等她從廁所回來就可以捉弄她！
But who's name do I write?
該寫誰的名字好呢？
What?
欸？
I really shouldn't look.
我實在不應該偷看
Well, maybe just a peek.
不然偷瞄一下就好
RO
（手）
"Ro"? So it's not my name…
第一個字的上半部是“手”？ 所以不是我的名字…
And it can't be anyone in this class, either.
也不是班上的同學
What? Then who is it?
咦？那會是誰？
Whatever! I'm gonna look!
不管了！我要看了！
ROUKAMIRO
（看走廊）
"Roukamiro"?
“看走廊”？
What?
什麼？
Look at the hallway?
叫我看走廊？
Ah!
啊！
Nishikata, you really are the best.
西片，你真的好好玩喔
This is exactly why I can't stop teasing you.
所以我才一直想捉弄你
Damn it.
可惡
Just you wait. I'm gonna get you back someday.
你等著瞧，總有一天我也會整到你
I doubt it.
我是不太相信啦
You missed out on a great chance!
畢竟你錯過了一個大好機會
Missed? What do you mean?
錯過？什麼意思？
Oh, nothing.
沒有
Look carefully at your partner while you draw.
繪畫時要仔細觀看你的夥伴
Nishikata, stop moving so much. Look at me.
西片，不要亂動，看著我
Okay! Switch places when you're done.
好了，完成後請交換位置
Here.
給你
Thank you.
謝謝
We've been staring and staring. You and me.
我們一直互看耶，你和我
Only because to draw we…
那只是為了畫畫…
I'm just doing the assignment.
為了畫畫才看你的
What will you do when you get home?
你回家後要做什麼？
A lot happened today so, maybe I'll go for a run.
今天發生了很多事 所以可能去跑步吧
"A lot"?
“很多事”？
What do you mean "a lot"?
你說“很多事”是指什麼？
A lot is a lot.
很多事就是很多事的意思
Right. Like being teased by me and beaten at everything?
對喔，像是被我捉弄 然後被罵之類的？
No, it's not that!
才不是！
Oh, yeah?
喔？
So, you want to run to cheer up. Like that?
所以，你想用跑步改善心情？
Can you run pretty far?
你可以跑很遠嗎？
Who knows?
這個嘛…
The other day, I ran to the Tada coast.
我有一天跑到了多田海岸
Really?
真的？
I sure did.
當然
That's pretty far away, isn't it?
那不是還挺遠的？
Are you sure?
真的嗎？
I'm not lying!
我可沒說謊
Hmm?
嗯…
That's pretty amazing if true.
如果是真的，那還挺厲害的
Good luck! See you tomorrow!
加油囉，明天見
Damn it.
可惡
She doesn't believe me at all!
她根本不相信我
All right.
好
I'll do it now and send a picture to prove it!
我現在就去跑 然後傳照片給她當作證明
Almost there!
快到了！
I made it!
我成功了！
I feel amazing!
感覺超棒的！
More importantly, I gotta send a picture to Takagi-san!
比起這個 重要的是傳照片給高木同學
All right.
好
Listen up, Takagi-san!
睜大眼睛看好了，高木同學
Witness my leg strength!
見證我的腳力吧！
Send!
傳送
PRETTY SUNSET, THANKS
（很美的夕陽，謝囉）
What? "Sunset"?
什麼？“夕陽”？
Not that! I want her to know how awesome it is that I ran here!
那不是重點 我是想讓她知道我跑到這裡多厲害
Oh, you didn't want to show me the sunset?
噢，所以不是要讓我看夕陽？
That's right, not the sunset…
對，不是夕陽…
Huh?
咦？
What? Huh?
欸？
Takagi-san? What are you doing here?
高木同學？你在這裡做什麼？
Huh?
咦？
Talking to you before made me want to see the sunset.
剛才跟你說話，讓我想看夕陽了
Do you want a drink?
要喝嗎？
Thanks.
謝了
I'm really happy.
我好高興喔
You ran all the way here to send me a picture of the sunset.
你跑了這麼遠 只是為了傳夕陽的照片給我
It's not like that…
才不是咧…
It's not?
不是嗎？
It's just…
我只是…
That I…
我…
You know, I ran all the way--
你知道，我跑了這麼遠…
Nishikata!
西片
What?
幹嘛？
It's so red, isn't it?
西片，好紅啊
Red? Am I blushing?
紅？我臉紅了嗎？
A beautiful red sunset!
真美麗的紅色夕陽
So pretty!
真漂亮
Huh?
咦？
Oh, the sunset!
噢，你在說夕陽啊
Yeah, it sure is.
對啊，就是嘛
It is a sunset, after all.
它畢竟是夕陽嘛
Well, it's not as red as you.
但它還是沒你紅
What?
什麼？
I'm glad I followed you here, Nishikata.
能跟著你來這裡真是太好了，西片
I even got to see the sunset with you.
還能這樣跟你一起看夕陽
Huh?
嗯？
It's amazing.
但還是好厲害啊
You actually ran all the way here!
你真的跑了這麼遠
You're amazing, Nishikata.
你真厲害，西片
It's not that big a deal.
這沒什麼啦
It's not?
沒什麼嗎？
So, you didn't send me a picture so I'd think you're awesome?
所以你傳照片給我 不是想讓我覺得你很厲害？
Of course not!
當然不是！
So, why did you?
那是為了什麼？
To show me the pretty sunset?
要給我看美麗的夕陽？
No, not that either.
不，也不是
I mean, yes! That's it.
我是說…對！沒錯
I just wanted to share the pretty sunset.
我只是要分享美麗的夕陽
I thought maybe you'd want to see it.
我想說你可能會想看
The sunset.
夕陽
I see!
這樣啊
So, you saw the pretty sunset and wanted me to see it too.
所以你看見了美麗的夕陽 然後也想讓我看看
Yes! Just like that.
對，就是這樣
It's kind of…
說起來…
It's like we're lovers.
我們這樣好像情侶喔
What? Really?
什麼？真的嗎？
Wow! You're turning red again!
哇！你又臉紅了
No, I'm not!
我才沒有
It's because of the sunset!
那是因為夕陽！
Can I have a sip?
我可以喝一口嗎？
Here.
換你
Don't you want some?
你不想喝一點嗎？
I'm not thirsty.
我現在不渴
Are you going to walk home?
你要走回家嗎？
Or do you plan on running again?
還是你打算再跑一次？
Hmm… Good question.
嗯…好問題
I guess I'll walk.
我應該用走的吧
Yeah?
喔？
Wanna ride together?
要一起騎嗎？
No, no it's fine! It's your bike.
不，沒關係，那是你的腳踏車
Could it be… you can't pedal with two people?
該不會…你不會載人？
No! I can but it's dangerous and…
才不是！我會啊，只是那樣太危險了
I'll just walk, okay?
我用走的就好了
Oh, I know! Could it be you're just embarrassed of being seen?
噢，我知道了，你怕被人看見？
No!
才不是！
The last guy who gave me a ride was so strong and cool!
上次載我的那個男生力氣大又帥氣呢
What?
什麼？
Well, I'll be going now.
好囉，我該走囉
Hey, wait!
嘿，等等！
I'll pedal.
我載你
Really? Can you pedal?
真的？你會載人？
Of course I can.
那當然
I'm ready.
我好了
Okay, here we go.
好，那出發囉
Thank you!
麻煩你了
Are you okay?
你還好嗎？
Of course, I'm okay!
那當然，我好得很
It was my dad!
是我爸爸！
What?
什麼？
The last person who gave me a ride, it was my dad.
上次騎車載我的人是我爸爸
It was?
是嗎？
Are you relieved?
你鬆了一口氣嗎？
Say what?
你說什麼？
Cut it out!
別學我啊！
Dinner's ready!
吃飯囉！
Coming!
來了！